A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Executive Director of the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission, 1970-2003
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Executive Director of the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission, 1970-2003
The Library of Virginia
42602
28 cubic foot (28 boxes)
Virginia Indigent Defense Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission, March 24, 2006.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Public Defender Commission was created on 10 April 1972 according to Chapter 2.1 of the Acts of Assembly. In 1972, the Commission consisted of five members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates in consultation with the Chairman of the Courts of Justice Committees of the Senate and House of Delegates. Following a successful pilot project, three offices were authorized in Augusta County, Virginia Beach, and the City of Roanoke in 1976. Offices were later added throughout the Commonwealth. The Commission establishes standards for the qualification of counsel appointed in capital cases and maintains lists of counsel for use by the circuit courts.
In 2004, the General Assembly created the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission to replace the Virginia Public Defender Commission. The mission of the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission is to enhance the quality of justice throughout Virginia by protecting the rights of the criminally accused through high quality, compassionate, and cost-effective legal representation. The Commission is responsible for providing oversight and support for all attorneys who furnish indigent defense service in the Commonwealth. The Commission consists of twelve members including the chairmen of the House and Senate Committees for Courts of Justice, the chairman of the Virginia State Crime Commission, the Executive Secretary of the Supreme Court, two attorneys officially designated by the Virginia State Bar, two persons appointed by the Governor, two persons appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates, and two persons appointed by the Senate Committee on Rules.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and subject files of the Executive Director of the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission, 1970-2003, document the planning, direction, and implementation of Commission programs and are evidence of actions and policy decisions. Contains memos, correspondence, financial records, complaints, minutes, annual reports, newsletters, and other sundry items belonging to the Executive Director of the Virginia Indigent Defense Commission. The director maintained various files related to public defender offices, studies, budget, commission meetings, etc.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged in original order.
Contents List
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1970-2003.
  - Motor Vehicles - State owned, 1989-1991. (Box 1)
  - Moving, Relocation Policy, 2000. (Box 1)
  - Rule 3A:15.1 - Newly Discovered Evidence, 2000. (Box 1)
  - Newsletter - The Virginia Defender, 1990-1995. (Box 1)
  - National Center for State Courts, 2001. (Box 1)
  - Newport News, 1972-2003. (Box 1)
  - No Parole legislation, 1989-1990. (Box 1)
  - Office lease procedures, 1996. (Box 1)
  - Sprinklers, 1998. (Box 1)
  - Overhead allowance, 1989. (Box 1)
  - Parking regulations, 1996. (Box 1)
  - Part-time employees - Memo re: nonpayment of accumulated sick leave, 1999. (Box 1)
  - Parole and Probation Compact - Administrators Association Manual, 1998. (Box 1)
  - Pay schedules, 1994. (Box 1)
  - Public Defender - Successful appeals, 1994. (Box 1)
  - Pinkerton - Miscellaneous, 1997. (Box 1)
  - Prince William County Bar Association - Interest in Capital Defense Seminar (NOVA), 2001. (Box 1)
  - Posting minutes online, 2002. (Box 1)
  - Public Defenders - Meeting preferences, 2002 June. (Box 1)
  - Proposed Office - Bristol, 1989-1992. (Box 1)
  - Proposed Office - Brunswick, Greensville, Surry, Sussex and Emporia, 1996. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Chesterfield, 1989. (Box 1)
  - Public Defender Office - Greensville / Brunswick Counties, 1989. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Loudoun, Fauquier, Rappahannock, 1987-1988. (Box 1)
  - Public Defender / Court Appointed Committee, 1995-1997. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Pittsylvania, 1999-2001. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Rockbridge / Buena Vista, 1989-1990. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Salem / Roanoke, 1990. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Bristol / Smyth / Washington, 1990. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Williamsburg / York, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Pre-Office - Richmond Office relocation, 1990. (Box 1)
  - Press releases, 1990-1991. (Box 1)
  - Procurement Policies, 1999. (Box 1)
  - Reappropriation request - Unexpended sum, 1989. (Box 1)
  - Resolution - Ann Frederick Downes, 2000. (Box 1)
  - Request for Commission Report, 1994. (Box 1)
  - Judge Robertson correspondence, 1992-1993. (Box 1)
  - Risk Management, 1998. (Box 1)
  - Resource Directory, 1998. (Box 1)
  - Proposed Pay Increase, 1996. (Box 1)
  - Public Defender Salaries - Editorials, Correspondence, 1993. (Box 2)
  - Pay increases, 1993. (Box 2)
  - Salary information, 1992. (Box 2)
  - Salary sheets, 1991. (Box 2)
  - Schley resignation, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Tuition / Payment, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Public Defender Program Summary of Public Defender Legislation, 1972-2003. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Acts of Assembly, 1993. (Box 2)
  - Youthful Offender Program, 2003. (Box 2)
  - Career Defender Committee, 1999. (Box 2)
  - Salaries - Career Defenders, 1999-2000. (Box 2)
  - Committee of District Courts, 1992-1995. (Box 2)
  - Committee on District Courts - SJR 186, 1994. (Box 2)
  - Drug Court Study Group - SJR 399, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Fatality Review Team Protocol, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Greensville Prison Committee, 1972-2003. (Box 2)
  - Investigators Association, Virginia State, 1989. (Box 2)
  - JLARC Study, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Legislation, 1972-2003. (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Juvenile Justice - Extended Focus Group, 1994. (Box 2)
  - Capital Standards, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Capital Case, 2003. (Box 2)
  - Capital Case - Standards and Certification, 2002-2003. (Box 2)
  - Capital Case - Judges, 2002. (Box 2)
  - Capital Case - List, 2002 Feb and Sept. (Box 2)
  - Capital Circuit Court, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Capital District Chief, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Capital Case - Judges, 2003 Feb. (Box 2)
  - Capital Case - Letters / Judges, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Capital List / Judges, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Capital letters to Judges, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Capital Cases - Representatives, 1991-1992. (Box 2)
  - Capital Defense Workshop, 2002 Nov. (Box 2)
  - Capital cases - Proportionality Review, 1996. (Box 3)
  - Alexandria - General correspondence, 1990-2004. (Box 3)
  - Alexandria - Budget, 1989-1995. (Box 3)
  - Bedford - General correspondence, 1989-2002. (Box 3)
  - Bedford - Pre-office information, 1989-1992. (Box 3)
  - Charlottesville / Albemarle - Pre-office information, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Charlottesville - Budget, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Danville - General correspondence, 1972-2003. (Box 3)
  - Fairfax - General correspondence, 1989-2000. (Box 3)
  - Fairfax - Future office space, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Fairfax material, 1993 June 18-19. (Box 3)
  - Fairfax / NOVA salaries, 1991. (Box 3)
  - Subcommittee Studying Procedural Aspects of Capital Cases, 1992-1993. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Law Foundation, 1992. (Box 3)
  - Counsel in Capital Cases - SB 852, 1991-1992. (Box 3)
  - Circuit Court Judges - Comments on Capital Case Standards, 1992. (Box 3)
  - Capital Cases, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Capital Case list, 1999. (Box 3)
  - Franklin - General correspondence, 1989-2003. (Box 4)
  - Fredericksburg - General correspondence, 1989-2000. (Box 4)
  - Fredericksburg - Expansion to include King George County, 1992. (Box 4)
  - Halifax - General correspondence, 1989-1992. (Box 4)
  - Leesburg - General correspondence, 1988-2000. (Box 4)
  - Lynchburg - General correspondence, 1991-2000. (Box 4)
  - Lynchburg - Personnel, 1992. (Box 4)
  - Lynchburg - Pre-office information, 1990-1991. (Box 4)
  - Martinsville - General correspondence, 1989-2000. (Box 4)
  - Martinsville - Pre-office information [Henry and Patrick Counties], 1990-1998. (Box 4)
  - Winchester - General correspondence, 1989-1998. (Box 5)
  - Capital Defense Workshop, 1994. (Box 5)
  - Capital Defense Workshop - Grant, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Capital Defense Workshop, 1998. (Box 5)
  - Capital Defense Workshop, 1999. (Box 5)
  - Public Defender Commission Dinner, 1999 June 16. (Box 5)
  - Interim Commission Meeting, 1999 June 4. (Box 5)
  - June Meeting, 1999. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Suffolk, undated. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Rockbridge, 1989. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Roanoke, 1975. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Pulaski, 1988. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Patrick County, 1997. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Budget - Martinsville, 1991. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Lynchburg, 1990. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Budget - King George FY93, 1992. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Halifax, 1989. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Fairfax, 1972-1974. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Fairfax, 1987. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Budget - Charlottesville, 1997. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Bedford, 1989. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Alexandria, 1979-1980. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Alexandria, 1987-1988. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Office information - Winchester, 1987-1988. (Box 5)
  - Proposed Budget - Richmond Expansion FY94, 1993. (Box 5)
  - Guardian Ad Litem, 1978. (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Information - Early Public Defender Studies, 1970-1971. (Box 5)
  - Petersburg - General correspondence, 1979-1995. (Box 6)
  - Petersburg - Employment notice information, 1995. (Box 6)
  - Portsmouth - General correspondence, 1989-2000. (Box 6)
  - Portsmouth - Annual reports, 1995. (Box 6)
  - Pulaski - General correspondence, 1989-1999. (Box 6)
  - Pulaski - Pre-office information, 1987-1988. (Box 6)
  - Richmond - General correspondence, 1989-1997. (Box 6)
  - Richmond - General District Court, 1989. (Box 6)
  - Roanoke - General correspondence, 1989-2000. (Box 6)
  - Staunton - General correspondence, 1972-1998. (Box 6)
  - Suffolk - General correspondence, 1989-2003. (Box 6)
  - Suffolk - Pre-office information, 1988. (Box 6)
  - Studies -Study Commission on District Courts, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Study on Crime Commission, 1997. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Study Appropriations Committee - Defense of Indigents in Virginia, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Bar Committees, 1988. (Box 7)
  - Studies - DJCP / Criminal Justices Services, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Joint Subcommittee on Public Defender System Defense of Indigents, 1986-1988. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Senate Finance Committee, 1988. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Projecting Costs (Spagenberg), 1985-1987. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Supreme Court Studies, 1982-1988. (Box 7)
  - Studies - Study Compensation - C/A v. PD, 1984-1994. (Box 7)
  - Public Defender Commission meeting, 1981 Oct. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1974. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1974 Nov. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1976 June. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1978. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1979. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1982. (Box 7)
  - Report of the Commission, 1983. (Box 7)
  - Public Defender Commission - Sixth Report, 1982. (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1972-1989. (Box 7)
  - Memos to Public Defenders, 1996-1997. (Box 8)
  - Public Defenders Correspondence, 1998. (Box 8)
  - Public Defenders Correspondence, 1999. (Box 8)
  - Memos to Public Defenders, 1995-1996. (Box 8)
  - Memos to Public Defenders, 1993-1994. (Box 8)
  - Memos to Public Defenders, 1993 Jan-1994 Nov. (Box 8)
  - Memos to Public Defenders, 1991-1992. (Box 8)
  - Memos to Public Defenders, 1989-1990. (Box 8)
  - Commission Member Correspondence, 1999. (Box 9)
  - Memos to Commission Members, 1996-1998. (Box 9)
  - Memos to Commission Members, 1995-1996. (Box 9)
  - Memos to Commission Members, 1993-1994. (Box 9)
  - Memos to Commission Members, 1992. (Box 9)
  - Memos to Commission Members, 1991. (Box 9)
  - Memos to Commission Members, 1990. (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1991-1992. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-1994. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1995. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1996. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1997. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1998. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, FY89-90. (Box 10)
  - Documents of Virginia Beach Public Defender Office, 1997-1999. (Box 11)
  - Public Defender Commission - Fiscal documents, 1998-1999. (Box 11)
  - Fener v. Public Defender Commission, 1998-1999. (Box 11)
  - Fener v. Public Defender Commission - Fiscal Policy Memos, 1997-1998. (Box 11)
  - Dept. of Accounts - Miscellaneous, 2003. (Box 12)
  - HB 478 - Adult Criminal History Records, 1990-1992. (Box 12)
  - Alcohol and other drugs - Policy, undated. (Box 12)
  - Commission Policy with regard to alcohol and other drugs, 1995. (Box 12)
  - Access to information infrastructure, 1997. (Box 12)
  - Administrative leave, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Americans with Disabilities Act, 1995-1996. (Box 12)
  - Appellate Division, 1998-2003. (Box 12)
  - Appeals - Public Defender Offices, 1995-1996. (Box 12)
  - Appellate Defender - part-time or full-time, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Appellate Defender - Sanders / Quality of Appeals, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Appellate Matters (Court of Appeals), 2002. (Box 12)
  - Appropriation Act - Relating to indebtedness of state agencies, 1998-2002. (Box 12)
  - Attorney-client Privilege - Miscellaneous, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Audit (1996 July 1-1998 Dec 31), 1999. (Box 12)
  - Auditor Reports, 1990-1991. (Box 12)
  - Audit letters, 1990-2000. (Box 12)
  - Authorized signatures, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Bail representation, 1997. (Box 12)
  - Baker case, 1999. (Box 12)
  - Bar dues - Local, 1989. (Box 12)
  - Bar dues - State, 1989. (Box 12)
  - Blue Ribbon Strike Force, 1994. (Box 12)
  - BNA Criminal Practical Manual, 1996. (Box 12)
  - Bonus / Leave Fact Sheet, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Boot Camp material, 1991-1997. (Box 12)
  - Bottled Water, 1997. (Box 12)
  - Budget - General, 1996. (Box 12)
  - Budget - Goal setting, 1995. (Box 12)
  - Budget - Revisions and additional costs, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Budget amendment, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Budget FY03, 2002. (Box 12)
  - Budget - Biennial, 2002-2004. (Box 12)
  - Budget amendments requests, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Budget FY00-02, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Budget, 2001. (Box 12)
  - Budget information - FY00 / DIT Services - Preparation, 1999. (Box 12)
  - Budget FY00, 1999. (Box 12)
  - Budget FY99, 1998. (Box 12)
  - Budget information, 1998-2000. (Box 13)
  - Budget, 1998-2000. (Box 13)
  - Budget Amendment FY98, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Budget, 1996-1998. (Box 13)
  - Budget amendement FY98, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Budget information, 1993-1996. (Box 13)
  - Brochure - Public Defender Mission, 2001. (Box 13)
  - Calendar Management and Delay Reduction - Workshop for Virginia's Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Campaign for an effective crime policy, 1993-1998. (Box 13)
  - Capital Defender Unit - Richmond (various positions), 2002. (Box 13)
  - Capital Ideas - Multi-County Public Defender (Georgia), 2000-2001. (Box 13)
  - Capital Square Complex - Master Plan Survey, 2003. (Box 13)
  - Carrying Concealed Weapons, 1997-2002. (Box 13)
  - Case Loads, Cost, etc., 1986-1988. (Box 13)
  - Case processing time guidelines, 1994. (Box 13)
  - Cellular phones - Investigator inquiry, 1996. (Box 13)
  - Children's Legal Protection News (newsletter), 1997. (Box 13)
  - CLE outline - Bar (historical background and duties), 1989. (Box 13)
  - CLE - Attendance forms and reports, 1999-2001. (Box 13)
  - CMRS, 1996-1997. (Box 13)
  - C/A Costs - Lee, Scott, Wise, 2001-2002. (Box 13)
  - Commonwealth Calendar, 2001. (Box 13)
  - Commonwealth Management Institute, 2002. (Box 13)
  - Community Corrections - Status Report, 2001. (Box 13)
  - Comparison Report (Cost / Savings) - Percentage of indigent cases handled (PD Offices), 1994-1995. (Box 13)
  - Compensation Plan, 1995. (Box 13)
  - Compensation Reform, 2000-2001. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Brown v. Scott and Bareford, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Devine and Miller, 1993. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Beltrante v. Leesburg Office, 1993. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Cook v. Harrer, 2002. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Writ of Mandamus / Eimer, 1997. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Fishback v. Cook, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Freas v. Gaynor, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Gonzales v. Legler, 1997. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Greene v. Spivey, 1995. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Dungee v. Teaster, 1992. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Jernigan and Bradley v. Sallee, 1993. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Hardy v. Pollard, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Langer (Bar Complaint), 1997. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Lundy v. Hanson, 1997. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Lux v. Bowers, 1997. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - McBride v. Commonwealth (Fairfax), 2002. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Nash v. Reves, 1989. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Scott v. Mosby, 1992. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Martin v. Petersburg and Wyatt, 1998. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Parker v. Legler and Barry, 1993. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Payne v. Huffman, 1993. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Pegram / Paner - Richmond Office, 1995. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Commonwealth (Kidwell) v. Richardson, 1994. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Terry v. Boggs, 1992. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Wenzler v. Hartsoe and Miller, 1993. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Spain v. Veness, 1994. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Miscellaneous, 1991. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Williams v. Schork, 2001. (Box 13)
  - Complaint - Wyatt v. Jones, 2003. (Box 13)
  - Compliance Review Report, 2001. (Box 13)
  - Comprehensive Community Corrections Act for Local Offenders and Pretrail Services Act, 1995-1998. (Box 13)
  - Commonwealth Currents, 1996-2000. (Box 13)
  - Community Corrections, 1996-1999. (Box 13)
  - Compass, 1997. (Box 14)
  - Compensation Reform, 2000. (Box 14)
  - Comptroller Directive No. 2-03, 2003. (Box 14)
  - Confidentialiry Policy, 1997. (Box 14)
  - Conflict of Interest Act, 1993. (Box 14)
  - Contingency Plan, 1991. (Box 14)
  - Connecticut Public Defender Office, 2003. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Jeff Brown, 1998-1999. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Kelly Hellams, 1997-1999. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Ed Ernouf, 2000. (Box 14)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2003. (Box 14)
  - Cost Comparisons, 2002. (Box 14)
  - Cost Comparisons - Supreme Court, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Cost Comparisons - Supreme Court, 2000-2001. (Box 14)
  - Cost Comparisons - Court-appointed Public Defender, 2000. (Box 14)
  - Cost Comparisons - Public Defender, 1996. (Box 14)
  - Cost and Feasibility of Redirecting CDI Funds, 1999-2002. (Box 14)
  - Council of Community Services, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Counsel for convicted felons on motion made, 2002. (Box 14)
  - Courts of Justice Committee - House of Delegates, 1998. (Box 14)
  - CPR training, 1996. (Box 14)
  - Credit Union, 1997. (Box 14)
  - Criminal Drug Statutes (revision), 1996. (Box 14)
  - Crime Commission study - HJR 178, 2000-2002. (Box 14)
  - Crime Commission - Miscellaneous, 2000-2002. (Box 14)
  - Criminal Defense Training, 2001. (Box 14)
  - Criminal Justice Services, 2003. (Box 14)
  - Criminal Justices Services - Community Oriented Justice, 1993-1998. (Box 14)
  - Defending a Capital Case in VA XIII - Scholarships, 2001. (Box 14)
  - Defending a Capital Case in VA XII - Scholarships, 2000. (Box 14)
  - Defending a Capital Case in VA XIV, 2002. (Box 14)
  - Defending a Capital Case - Washington and Lee, 2003. (Box 14)
  - Defending a Capital Case in VA XV, 1972-2003. (Box 14)
  - Deferred Compensation, 1994. (Box 14)
  - Economic Interests - Conflict of Interest Statement, 2001. (Box 14)
  - Leave Policy, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Personnel and Training, Dept. of - Compensation Study, 1994. (Box 14)
  - Career Transition Center, 1994. (Box 15)
  - Diversity within our system, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Diversity training / Judiciary and Virginia Bar Association, 1997. (Box 15)
  - Driving records, 1993. (Box 15)
  - Drug Court - SJR 399 workgroup, 2001. (Box 15)
  - Drug Court - Study workshop, 2001. (Box 15)
  - Email addresses, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Employment ads, 1989-1998. (Box 15)
  - Employer contact information, 2003. (Box 15)
  - Employment law, 1994-2002. (Box 15)
  - Exceptional circumstances - Defendants not indigent but requiring special counsel, 1994. (Box 15)
  - Expenditure statements, 2001-2003. (Box 15)
  - Fair Trial Initiative, 2002. (Box 15)
  - Family and Medical Leave, 1993-1997. (Box 15)
  - Firearms (Concealed weapons) - Memo to Public Defenders, 1997. (Box 15)
  - Fixed Assets, 1997-2004. (Box 15)
  - Fixed Felony Committee, 1998. (Box 15)
  - Franklin County - Public Defender inquiry, 2001. (Box 15)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1998. (Box 15)
  - General Assembly, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Grievance procedure, 1997-1998. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - General Information, 1995-1997. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Pilot planning group, 1994. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem applicants - Alexandria Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court, 1995. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem applicants - King and Queen, King William, New Kent, 1995. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Reply from district judges, 1994. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Interim reports, 1994-1996. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - 9th Juvenile and Domestic Court, 1994-1996. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Alexandria, 1994-1996. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Harrisonburg / Rockingham, 1994-1996. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Alexandria, 1994-1996. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Guidance document, 2001. (Box 15)
  - Guardian ad litem - Guidance documents with Registrar of Regulations, 1997-2000. (Box 15)
  - Grants - Concept papers, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Grant information - Dept. of Criminal Justice Services, 1998. (Box 15)
  - Grants - Miscellaneous, 1995-1996. (Box 15)
  - Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Project - Research findings, 2004. (Box 16)
  - Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Project - Conference attendees, 1972-2003. (Box 16)
  - Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Project - Grant, 1994. (Box 16)
  - Juvenile Law and Education Seminar, 1997-1999. (Box 16)
  - Juveniles in confinement, 1998. (Box 16)
  - Habeas Corpus - State / Federal, 1992. (Box 16)
  - Health Benefits, undated. (Box 16)
  - History - Public Defender Commission, undated. (Box 16)
  - HJR 32 - Magistrate System - Focus Groups, 2002. (Box 16)
  - HJR 131 - Advisory Committee, 1996. (Box 16)
  - HJR 687 - Crime Commission, 2001. (Box 16)
  - Integrated Decision Support System (IDSS) Pilot Study, 1996-1997. (Box 16)
  - Integrated Criminal Justice Information System (ICJIS), 2001. (Box 16)
  - Integrated Human Resource Information System (IHRIS), 1999. (Box 16)
  - Internal Control Statement, 2002. (Box 16)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1989-2004. (Box 16)
  - Interview Material, undated. (Box 16)
  - Interpreters - Contracted (State), 2000. (Box 16)
  - Issue and Answers - Secretary's meeting, 2000 May 2-3. (Box 16)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1999-2000. (Box 16)
  - Judicial Circuits and Districts of Virginia, 1999. (Box 16)
  - Judicial System, 1997. (Box 16)
  - Judge Thomas O. Jones - Reappointment, 1997. (Box 16)
  - JLARC Study of Information Systems, 2002. (Box 16)
  - JLARC Review, 1997. (Box 16)
  - Juvenile Justice, Dept. of, 2000. (Box 16)
  - Juvenile Law Study Committee, 1997. (Box 16)
  - Juvenile materials - Miscellaneous, 1997-1999. (Box 16)